Philip M. Sheppard Papers 1911-1976 1940-1976 Mss.Ms.Coll.65
American Philosophical Society
Philip M. Sheppard Papers
Bulk, 1940-1976
1911-1983
Mss.Ms.Coll.65
American Philosophical Society
16.5 Linear feet
A geneticist and educator, Philip Macdonald Sheppard was head of the Department of Genetics at the University of Liverpool from 1963-1976. His research centered on polymorphism, mimicry, blood groups, genetic disease, and speciation, using a variety of subjects, including the gastropod Cepaea nemoralis, butterflies, and humans. He may be best remembered for his classic study of industrial melanism in the pepper moth Biston betularia. The Sheppard Papers (1911-1983; bulk dates, 1940-76) contain correspondence, subject files, notes, and manuscripts that document Sheppard's life as a geneticist. The earliest piece in the collection is a lepidopterist's notebook from 1911, possibly J. R. Hobhouse's, however the bulk dates from 1940 to 1976, Sheppard's most productive and influential years. Among other things, these materials document Sheppard's research on the Scarlet Tiger moth, swallowtail butterflies, and ABO blood groups in humans, as well as his position as head of the Department of Genetics at the University of Liverpool.
Sheppard, P. M. (Philip Macdonald), 1921-1976
General note
For biographical information see The Royal Society of London. Biographical Memoirs of Fellows 23 (1977), 465.
Dictionary of Scientific Biography 18, 815.
Ibid.
Nature 266 (10 Mar. 1977), 201.
University of Liverpool Recorder 74 (Apr. 1977), 4-7.
Royal Society of London,486.
The University of Liverpool Recorder, 4.
Genetics Note
This collection contains materials which relate to the history of genetics.
Acton, A. B. Correspondence (2 folders) 1954-1969
Cain, Arthur James Correspondence (2 folders) 1950-1983
Clarke, Cyril Astley Correspondence (16 folders) 1952-1976
Crick, Francis H. C. Correspondence (2 items) 1962
Darlington, Cyril Dean Correspondence (14 items) 1951-1969
Demerec, Milislav Correspondence (5 items) 1955-1959
Dobzhansky, Theodosius Correspondence (2 folders) 1953-1971
Evolution Correspondence (1 folder) 1960-1976
Fisher, Ronald Aylmer Correspondence (2 folders) 1946-1961
Ford, Edmund Brisco Correspondence (16 folders) 1949-1976
Haldane, John Burdon Sanderson Correspondence (2 items) 1959, n.d.
Hobhouse, John Richard -- Research notebook Notebooks (1 item) 1911
Huxley, Julian Correspondence (2 items) 1958
Kettlewell, Henry Bernard Davis Correspondence (5 folders) 1952-1976
Kimura, Motoo Correspondence (51 items) 1955-1976
Krimbas, Costas B. Correspondence (5 items) 1967-1968
Lerner, Isadore Michael Correspondence (8 items) 1962-1971
Lewontin, Richard Charles Correspondence (15 items) 1955-1973
Mansfield, Philip R. A. Correspondence (32 items) 1957-1960
Mayr, Ernst Correspondence (21 items) 1953-1969
McConnell, Richard Bonar Correspondence (46 items) 1955-1971
Nuffield Foundation Correspondence (4 folders) 1954-1975
Sheppard, Philip M. -- Research notes Notebooks (1.5 linear feet, 53 notebooks) 1911, 1940-1976
Sheppard, Philip M. -- Subject files Manuscripts (1 linear foot) 1952-1976
Stern, Curt Correspondence (1 item) 1956
Turner, John R. G. Correspondence (15 folders) 1959-1976
Van Someren, Victor Gurner Logan Correspondence (2 folders) 1956-1968
Wallace, Bruce Correspondence (7 items) 1954-1963
List of Photographs
Photographs, mostly snapshots, have not separated from accompanying materials and appear in the collection in the following folders:
Series I
Ashton, Geoffrey C. 1957 April 25 3 images
Butler, Roy 1972 Feb. 3- of Derek Roff
Cadbury, James 1964 May 6
Clarke, Cyril A. Image of swallowtail butterfly; 1976 1955 May 5; 1957 June 27 1 image (2 copies)
Eff, Donald [1957] no photo. but packing slip which reads, "Dried Botanical Specimens for Scientific Research: No Commercial Value"
Fredga, Karl 1976 July 7
Kettlewell, H.B.D. 1966 Oct. 15; 1967 June 6
Kimura, Motoo 1958 Oct. 8
Rothschild, Miriam 1974 Jan. 26
Thompson, Mary n.d. - of Samantha and Lisa Thompson
Turner, John R. G. 1968 June 20 - 4 images.; 1973 2 images.
Watkins & Doncaster Not a photo, but mounting pins for insects
Series II
"f. carbonaria Distribution on British Isles" n.d.
"Protective Coloration in Some British Moths" [1963?] 2 images
Related Archival Materials note
The Arthur J. Cain Papers (Ms. Coll. 63) include related material on gastropod genetics and biology.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
This collection was a gift of Arthur J. Cain, a colleague of Philip M. Sheppard from the University of Liverpool. Professor William Provine arranged for the shipment of the collection from England. The papers were received in July 1989 and assigned accession no. 1989 2937ms. Reprints found in the collection have been removed to the APS printed materials collection.
Scope and Contents note
The Philip Macdonald Sheppard Papers (1911-1983; bulk dates, 1940-76) contain correspondence, subject files, notes, and manuscripts that document Sheppard's life as a geneticist. The earliest piece in the collection is a lepidopterist's notebook from 1911, possibly J. R. Hobhouse's, however the bulk dates from 1940 to 1976, Sheppard's most productive and influential years. Among other things, these materials document Sheppard's research on the Scarlet Tiger moth, swallowtail butterflies, and ABO blood groups in humans, as well as his position as head of the Department of Genetics at the University of Liverpool. The most recent items include correspondence between his colleague Arthur J. Cain and Sir Cyril A. Clarke regarding the loan of Sheppard's correspondence.
The papers (34 boxes; 16.75 linear feet) are divided into three series:
Series I. Correspondence (28 boxes; 14 linear feet)
Series II. Subject Files (2 boxes; 1 linear foot)
Series III. Research Notes and Notebooks (3 boxes; 1.5 linear feet)
Series I-III. Oversize Materials (1 box; .25 linear feet)
Oversize materials follow the same series arrangement as noted above. Cross referencing to oversize material appears on the folders in the standard size boxes. Reprints have been removed from the collection; consult the card catalog for printed materials to retrieve those items.
Biographical/Historical note
Philip Macdonald Sheppard (1921-1976) was a geneticist whose primary interests included human and population genetics, evolution, medicine, and certain aspects of ecology and ecological genetics. He was especially concerned with polymorphism, mimicry, blood groups and disease, and the genetics of species differences (See Series II, Subject Files under Biographical Information). His important contributions to genetics include: his studies on natural selection in the polymorphic land snail ( Cepaea nemoralis) in collaboration with A. J. Cain; his joint studies with Cyril Clarke on Rhesus hemolytic disease in newborn babies which led to the development of a preventive treatment; and the genetics and evolution of mimicry in butterflies.
Philip Macdonald Sheppard was born on 27 July 1921 in Marlborough, Wiltshire, England to George Sheppard, a schoolmaster, and Alison Macdonald. He was educated at Marlborough College from 1935 to 1939, served with the Royal Air Force Volunteer Reserve from 1940 to 1945, and was a prisoner-of-war from 1942 to 1945. He studied at Worcester College, Oxford University from 1946 to 1948. In 1948, he received a second class honours degree in Zoology, and was subsequently awarded the Christopher Welch Research Scholarship. Under E. B. Ford's guidance, he studied for the D.Phil. and obtained the degree in 1951. His thesis was entitled "Genetic and Evolutionary Problems in wild populations of the Lepidoptera and other forms."
Sheppard was a Junior Research Officer in the Department of Zoology at Oxford from 1951 to 1956. In 1954, he was awarded a fellowship by the Rockefeller Foundation which enabled him to work for one year with Theodosius Dobzhansky at Columbia University, New York. He was appointed Senior Lecturer in Genetics in the Department of Zoology at the University of Liverpool in 1956, was promoted to Reader in Genetics in 1959, and, in 1963, became the first Professor of Genetics at Liverpool. He continued in that position until his death.
An excellent statistician and geneticist, "[Sheppard's] genius lay in the experimental approach, whether it was with butterflies, moths, snails or man." 1 His research on the moth Panaxia dominula (the Scarlet Tiger), and Cepaea nemoralis (the land snail) showed the effects of various kinds of natural selection in controlling the genetic composition of wild populations. His work on Panaxia, which continued the work begun by R.A. Fisher and E.B. Ford, "was extremely influential in establishing the view that natural selection was the all-powerful process in generating evolutionary change." 2
Much of Sheppard's research was done in collaboration with other scientists. With Cyril Clarke, he carried out his work on the genetics of butterfly mimicry and the prevention of rhesus hemolytic disease. Their work on mimicry in Papilio dardanus and P. memnon, and Heliconius melpomene and H. erato led to the "discovery of 'supergenes,' tightly linked blocks of functionally independent genes, all controlling different aspects of the mimetic pattern." In an effort to demonstrate that natural selection was active in human populations, "Clarke and Sheppard investigated the correlations of blood groups with disease... Believing also that the rhesus blood groups were controlled by a supergene similar to that found in mimetic butterflies, they then turned their attention to the chief form of natural selection known to work on these blood groups, hemolytic disease of the newborn. This led to an enduring advance in pediatrics: the prevention of this condition--a major cause of miscarriage, infant death, and brain damage--by injecting with rhesus antibody those mothers known to be at risk." 3
Research conducted with Cyril Clarke, R.B. McConnell, and David Price Evans included a project on sibship and antigen studies in duodenal ulcers, blood groups and secretion in carcinoma of the stomach, tylosis and carcinoma of the oesophagus, PTC tasting and thyroid diseases, serological study of mucosa cells, biochemical study of blood group substances, Klinefelter's syndrome, secretor character and sub-fertility, secretor character in gastric ulcers, secretor character in mitral stenosis, and other blood group systems in hemolytic disease of the newborn due to Rh incompatibility (See Series I, Cyril A. Clarke, Sept. 1958).
Sheppard also made important studies on the evolution of dominance, the genetics of industrial melanism in moths, particularly Biston betularia (the pepper moth), and heavy metal tolerance in plants, principally in Mimulus (monkey musk). He was invited by the World Health Organization to investigate the population genetics of insecticide-resistant mosquitos ( Aedes) in Southeast Asia; this work was done in collaboration with W.W. Macdonald. His research also included the genetics of schizophrenia, anencephaly and spina bifida in humans. 4 With J.J.B. Gill, Sheppard examined the genetics of prostrate forms in broom ( Cytisus).
His research on how natural selection works and its effect on the genetic constitution of organisms resulted in Natural Selection and Heredity (1958) and numerous other studies of butterflies, moths, snails and human medical genetics. Although initially uncomfortable in front in the lecture hall, Sheppard fashioned himself into a "first-class lecturer." He lectured at many institutions in Great Britain and in the United States. He was "an invited speaker at many conferences, a guest of the Australian Universities Vice-Chancellors' Committee in 1967, Visiting Professor of Genetics at Davis, California in 1968, and a Royal Society Leverhulme Visiting Professor in Brazil in 1971." 5 In 1973, Sheppard edited Practical Genetics, a book designed to aid instructors of genetics.
In 1966 and again in 1967, Sheppard excited public interest in genetics by organizing "a highly successful television series with Granada, compris[ed of] ten programmes on evolution. He devised the series and acted as adviser throughout, and his idea was that the programmes taken together should give a good general account of the theory of evolution, its origins and the modern evidence for its validity." 6
Though not an avid committee member, Sheppard served on several committees throughout his career. These include the Committee of the Genetical Society of Great Britain from 1953-55, the Aldabra Research Committee of the Royal Society, and on the Sub-Committee of the Research Grants Committee of the D.S.I.R. from 1964 to 1965. He also served on various committees of the University of Liverpool, "especially the Ness Gardens Management Committee,... the Fluoridation Committee of the Royal College of Physicians,...the University Grants Committee's Biological Sciences Sub-Committee, and on occasion in relation to committees of the World Health Organization." 7
Sheppard was elected a fellow of the Royal Society of London in 1965, and was awarded its Darwin Medal in 1974. In 1975, he received the Gold Medal for Zoology from the Linnaean Society, and, in recognition of his work with Cyril Clarke on rhesus factors, was made an Honorary Fellow of the Royal College of Physicians in the same year.
Sheppard died of acute leukemia in Liverpool on October 17, 1976. He was survived by his wife, Patricia Beatrice Lee, whom he had married in 1948, and by their three sons.
Ayala, Fransisco José, 1934-; Brower, Lincoln P.; Brown, Keith S.; Cain, Arthur J. (Arthur James), 1921-1999; Clarke, Cyril A., (Cyril Astley); Dobzhansky, Theodosius Grigorievich, 1900-1975; Fisher, Ronald Aylmer, Sir, 1890-1962; Ford, E. B. (Edmund Briscoe), 1901-; Kettlewell, H. B. D. (Henry Bernard Davis); Lewontin, Richard C.; MacDonald, W. W.; Mayr, Ernst, 1904-2005; McConnell, Richard B.; Royal Society (Great Britain). Aldabra Research Committee; Royal Society (Great Britain).; Science Research Council (Great Britain); Turner, John R. G.; University of Liverpool; Adaptation (Biology); Biston betularia; Blood; Evolution (Biology); Genetics; Genetics--Research; Lepidoptera--Genetics; Manuscripts; Medical genetics; Mimicry (Biology)--Genetic aspects; Natural selection; Notebooks; Snails -- Genetics.; Speciation
- Series I. Correspondence, 1946-1983; 28 boxes, 14 lin. feet
  Scope and Contents note
  incoming and outgoing manuscript and typescript letters, carbons, and postcards generated during Sheppard's career. Series I is arranged alphabetically by correspondent's name and then chronologically within each file. It is the largest series of the collection.
  Chronologically, the correspondence is rather evenly distributed. Short papers and some photographs appear in a correspondent's file when relevant to accompanying correspondence. Colleagues' reprints and draft articles containing significant marginalia are included in this series. Unidentified correspondence has been filed as "Unidentified" and is arranged chronologically. The correspondence is primarily in English, though there are a few letters in French, and Italian; non-English references are noted on the folder. The foreign language items are usually from the correspondent; Sheppard's replies are generally in English.
  Correspondents include geneticists, biologists, doctors and other members of the medical profession, current and former students, officials of various organizations, publishers, and interested amateur geneticists. Subjects covered in this series include: the genetics of Panaxia dominula, Cepaea nemoralis, Papilio, Cytisus, Mimulus, and the ABO blood groups. There is some correspondence on the breeding of domestic animals, including chickens, sheep and cats. Letters of reference are filed in the subject's file. Book reviews appear in several publishers' files. The files of the Medical Research Council, the Royal Society and the Science Research Council primarily contain research proposals accompanied by Sheppard's critical appraisals.
  Of special interest among Sheppard's correspondents are Cyril Clarke and Richard McConnell for information on blood group research, E.B. Ford for research data on Panaxia dominula, and John R.G. Turner for research on Heliconius. For correspondence on Papilio research see especially: Cyril A. Clarke, Ronald Fisher, V.G.L. Van Someren, P.R.A. Mansfield, Motoo Kimura, and A.B. Acton. The Nuffield Foundation file contains progress reports by Sheppard on his blood group and Papilio research with Cyril Clarke. For information on Cepaea see the file for Arthur Cain. There is very little correspondence on the administration of the Department of Genetics at the University of Liverpool. Much of that material is probably available at the University itself.
  Among Sheppard's correspondents are:
  Acton, A. B.
  Ashton, Geoffrey C.
  Brower, Lincoln P.
  Cain, Arthur J.
  Clarke, Cyril A.
  Crick, Francis H. C.
  Dobzhansky, Theodosius
  Ford Edmund Brisco
  Fisher, Ronald A.
  Huxley, Julian S.
  Kettlewell, Henry Bernard Davis
  McConnell, Richard B.
  Macdonald, W. W.
  Smith, Cedric A. B.
  Turner, John R. G.
  Van Someren, V. G. L.
  The most recent correspondence is from Arthur Cain in 1983 regarding letters of R.I. Vane-Wright which were loaned to Cyril Clarke. Only one of the letters discussed appears among Sheppard's papers.
  - A.E.R.E., 1956 (Box Series I-1)
  - Abdulali, Humayun, 1974 (Box Series I-1)
  - Abdulali, Salman, 1974 (Box Series I-1)
    -See also Ser.I, Macdonald, W.W.
  - Abercrombie, Michael, 1967 (Box Series I-1)
  - Abrams, Tom, 1975 (Box Series I-1)
  - Academic Press, Inc., 1961 (Box Series I-1)
  - Ackroyd, Ian, 1966 (Box Series I-1)
  - Acton, A. B., 1954-1969; 2 folders (Box Series I-1)
    Biographical and personal data; Cain, Arthur James; Conferences and symposia; Cytogenetics; Drosophila genetics; Educational matters; Genetics -- Butterflies, moths; Graduate study -- Great Britain; Haldane, John Burdon Sanderson; Population genetics; Statistics, biostatistics, biometrics; Travel -- Canada; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.
    - Folder 1, 1954-1959 (Box Series I-1)
    - Folder 2, 1960-1969; n.d. (Box Series I-1)
  - Adair, Annie L., 1974-76 (Box Series I-1)
  - Adams, Michael J., 1972-76 (Box Series I-1)
    -See also Ser.I, Clarke, Cyril A.
  - Adams, R., 1975 (Box Series I-1)
  - Adamson, A.C. (Box Series I-1)
    -See Ser.I, Hawe, Philip
  - Addison, [?], n.d. (Box Series I-1)
  - Ae, Shigeru Albert, 1956-58; 1972-76 (Box Series I-1)
  - Agacino, Morales, 1953 (Box Series I-1)
  - Agricultural Research Council, 1965-71 (Box Series I-1)
  - Air Ministry, 1961 (Box Series I-1)
  - Aird, Ian, 1953 (Box Series I-1)
  - Al-Ani, Farouk Y., 1970-74 (Box Series I-1)
  - Albanese, Rosario, 1976 (Box Series I-1)
  - Alexander, W.G., 1965 (Box Series I-1)
  - Allan, Adrian, 1974 (Box Series I-1)
  - Allard, R.W., 1956; 1967-71 (Box Series I-1)
  - Allen, Courtney P., 1958-59 (Box Series I-1)
  - Allen, Sally Lyman, 1955-56 (Box Series I-1)
  - Allen, W. Ross (Box Series I-1)
    - Folder 1, 1969-May 1970 (Box Series I-1)
    - Folder 2, Jun. 1970-72; n.d. (Box Series I-1)
  - Allison, A.C., 1953-58 (Box Series I-1)
  - Amadon, Dean, 1963 (Box Series I-1)
  - Amateur Entomologists' Society, 1955; 1959 (Box Series I-1)
  - American Eugenics Society, 1963 (Box Series I-1)
  - American Express Company, Inc., 1957-60 (Box Series I-1)
  - American Journal of Human Genetics, 1954 (Box Series I-1)
    -See Ser.II, Linkage and the Blood Groups
  - American Journal of Physical Anthropology (Box Series I-1)
    -See Ser.I, Lugg, J.W.H.
  - American Naturalist, 1953-60; 1968-76 (Box Series I-1)
  - Amos, D.B., 1953 (Box Series I-1)
  - Amos, R., 1964 (Box Series I-1)
  - Anderson, Alun. M., 1969 (Box Series I-1)
  - Anderson, G.E., 1967-69 (Box Series I-1)
  - Anderson, Robert, 1970 (Box Series I-1)
  - Andres, P.N., 1966 (Box Series I-1)
  - Andrewartha, H.G., 1967 (Box Series I-1)
  - Andrews, Peter (Box Series I-1)
  - Angseesing, Joseph P.A. (Box Series I-1)
    Cook, E.R.
    Elgood, J.H.
    Lewin, S.
    [Turner?], John [R.G.]
    Walker, S.
    - Folder 1, 1965-69 (Box Series I-1)
    - Folder 2, 1970-72 (Box Series I-1)
  - Angus, Donald S., 1976 (Box Series I-1)
  - Angus, John, 1969-71 (Box Series I-1)
  - Angus, William J., 1973 (Box Series I-1)
  - Annual Review of Ecology and Systematics, 1973 (Box Series I-1)
  - Annual Review of Entomology, 1966 (Box Series I-1)
  - Anti-Locust Research Centre, 1953 (Box Series I-1)
  - Antonovics, Janis, 1967-73 (Box Series I-1)
  - Appleton-Century-Crofts, 1967 (Box Series I-1)
  - Applied Research Laboratories, 1972 (Box Series I-1)
  - Arbani, Shah Nawaz, 1966 (Box Series I-1)
  - Archbold, R., 1959 (Box Series I-1)
  - Archer, Nora, 1953 (Box Series I-1)
  - Archer, Richard K. (Box Series I-1)
    -See Ser.I, Clarke, Cyril A., 1966
  - Ardley, J.H., 1961 (Box Series I-1)
  - The Ark, 1974 (Box Series I-1)
  - Arndt, Stephan, 1972 (Box Series I-1)
  - Arnold, Richard, 1965-72 (Box Series I-1)
  - [Arnott], Melville (Box Series I-1)
    -See Ser.I, Clarke, Cyril A.
  - Arunachalam, V., 1970 (Box Series I-1)
  - Ashhurst, Doreen E., 1956; 1968 (Box Series I-1)
  - Ashton, Eric H., 1958-59 (Box Series I-1)
  - Ashton, Geoffrey C. (Box Series I-1)
    Pumphrey, R.J.
    - Folder 1, 1957-59 (Box Series I-1)
    - Folder 2, 1960-73 (Box Series I-1)
  - Aslib, 1972 (Box Series I-1)
  - Asmer Seeds Ltd. (Box Series I-1)
    -See Ser.I, Bradshaw, A.D.
  - Associated Book Publishers Ltd., 1967 (Box Series I-1)
  - Associated-Rediffusion Ltd., 1957 (Box Series I-1)
  - Associated Television Ltd., 1959 (Box Series I-1)
  - Atkins, Gregory J., 1969-73 (Box Series I-2)
  - Atkinson, D.R., 1964 (Box Series I-2)
  - Atlay, R.D., 1970 (Box Series I-2)
  - Augustin, R., 1964-65; 1976 (Box Series I-2)
  - Australian Vice-Chancellors' Committee, 1966-67 (Box Series I-2)
  - Ayala, Francisco J., 1974 (Box Series I-2)
  - Baird & Tatlock, 1969 (Box Series I-2)
  - Bakare, Olatunji, 1966 (Box Series I-2)
  - Baker, Alan J.M., 1971 (Box Series I-2)
  - Baker, C.R., 1953 (Box Series I-2)
  - Baker, H.G., 1956 (Box Series I-2)
  - Baker, John, 1954 (Box Series I-2)
  - Ballard, G.B., 1952 (Box Series I-2)
  - Banbury, G.H., 1956 (Box Series I-2)
  - Harry Banister & Partners, 1962 (Box Series I-2)
  - Bar, Ze'ev, 1970 (Box Series I-2)
  - Barigozzi, Claudio, 1951 (Box Series I-2)
  - Barker, John F., 1962-72 (Box Series I-2)
  - Barnes, [?] (Box Series I-2)
    -See Ser.I, Kettlewell, H.B.D.
  - Barnes, B., 1967 (Box Series I-2)
  - Barnes, Brian W., 1972 (Box Series I-2)
    Kearsey, M.J.
    -See also Ser.I, Kearsey, M.J.
  - Barnes, O., 1955 (Box Series I-2)
  - Barnes, W.H.F., 1967-69 (Box Series I-2)
    -See also Ser.I, Booth, Norman
  - Barraclough, O., 1959 (Box Series I-2)
  - Barrett, John A., 1969-74 (Box Series I-2)
  - Barrett, J.H., 1961 (Box Series I-2)
  - Barrington, Ernest J.W., 1961; 1967-75 (Box Series I-2)
  - Bartlett, M.S., 1970 (Box Series I-2)
  - Barton, Derek (Sir), 1973 (Box Series I-2)
    [Heets?], Edwin
  - Bateman, Angus J., 1956-65 (Box Series I-2)
  - Battaglia, Bruno, 1962; 1971-72 (Box Series I-2)
  - Batten, John L., 1970-76 (Box Series I-2)
  - Baverstock, Peter, 1968 (Box Series I-2)
  - Baxby, Derrick, n.d. (Box Series I-2)
  - Baxter, J.T. (Box Series I-2)
    -See Ser.I, Davies, G.O.
  - Baxter, S.J., 1975 (Box Series I-2)
  - Bayley, P.C., 1962 (Box Series I-2)
  - Baynes, E.S.Q., 1951-52 (Box Series I-2)
  - Beard, J.P., 1966 (Box Series I-2)
  - Beardmore, John A., 1962-76 (Box Series I-2)
  - Beatty, R.A., 1969-71 (Box Series I-2)
  - Beazley, John M. (Box Series I-2)
  - Beck, J., 1969 (Box Series I-2)
  - Becker, Peter, 1971 (Box Series I-2)
  - Beechey, G.D.S., 1966 (Box Series I-2)
  - Beer, Ian, 1956 (Box Series I-2)